Walt Munson Cartoons
Walt Munson Cartoons
1965-1970
Munson, Walt.
1.67 linear ft.
27 original sports cartoons and 7 proofs.
2651145
Biographical History
Walt Munson was an American sports cartoonist and illustrator.
Munson worked as a cartoonist for the New Haven Register from approximately the early 1940s through 1974. Prior to this, he drew the single panel cartoon, Such is Life and illustrated comic postcards.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Walt Munson Cartoons are divided into two series. Cartoons (1965-1970, undated) contains 27 original sports cartoons produced for the New Haven Register. A variety of sports are caricatured, however Munson's attention is frequently on college sports played by Yale University and other Ivy League teams.
Sixteen cartoons have dates stamped on the back. The cartoons vary in size with the largest measuring approximately 11 1/2" x 17 1/2". The cartoons were drawn primarily with ink on illustration board and Graphix paper. Some were drawn with crayon and traces of pencil are visible.
Proofs and Tearsheet (1970, undated) contains 7 items. Several are about the interruption of college sporting events by campus protests and demonstrations.
Arrangement of the Collection
Dated items are arranged in chronological order and undated items are arranged in alphabetical order.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Munson, Walt.; Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Baseball -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Basketball -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Boxing -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Caricatures and cartoons -- Connecticut.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- Connecticut.; Cartoonists -- United States.; College sports -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Demonstrations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Football -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Golf -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Hockey -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Horse racing -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Ivy League (Athletic conference) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Sports -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Student protesters -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Yale University -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Proofs (printed matter); Tear sheets.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Walt Munson, 1967, 1969, 1971 and 1972.
Inventory
- Cartoons
  - 1965 (Oversize 1)
    Feb 5: Will You Be My Valentine: horse racing, track and field, Yale University, wrestling, Brown University, Ivy League
    Oct 9: Sportsnotes Scientist to Spend $63,000 to Learn Why Birds Warble
  - 1967 (Oversize 1)
    Apr 8: The Greeks had a word for it "Go man go!": baseball, chariot racing, Yale University, basketball, Muhammad Ali
    Jul 8: Box Office Draw: baseball
    Oct 14: Sports Love in Bloom: New York Mets, Washington Senators, Boston Red Sox, hockey
  - 1968 (Oversize 1)
    Jan 13: [Superbowl]: Oakland Raiders, Green Bay Packers
    Feb 3: Chef's Special: Yale University, Ivy League
    Mar 1: Back to the Drawing Board: sports stadiums and arenas
    Oct 8: What Is Your Favorite Sport?
    Oct 12: PenPost Mortem: World Series, football, Columbia, Mickey Lolich
  - 1969 (Oversize 1)
    Oct 11: It's the new sports compact made isn't it?: football, basketball, hockey, baseball, New York Mets
  - 1970 (Oversize 1)
    Jan 17: National Collegiate Athletic Association Puts Yale University Athletes on two-year probation: NCAA, Yale University
    Feb 28: Speaking of Air Pollution- Around the Sportspark...we are: sports heroes
    Apr 13: Ivy League Completes Budget Talks
    May 9: Oh! Somewhere in this favored landed the sun is shining bright...
    May 25: Book Review: Jim Bouton, horse racing, New York Mets, Boston Patriots
  - Undated (Oversize 1)
    Ah Yes, Sweet smell of flowers in spring sportstime!: baseball, hockey, basketball, boxing
    Along sportslines: golf, sportswriters
    Coming Attractions at Home and Away: football, Harvard, Yale University, Michigan State, Notre Dame
    Let's not disappoint dear old mother: Yale University, Ivy League
    Our National Pastime: football
    Picket Lines: boxing, golf, Navy, cheerleaders (Jan. 8)
    Seasonal Greeting Cards are in the mail: Leo Durocher, Eddie Stanky, Boston Red Sox, boxing, NCAA, Yale University, Al Dark
    Stop the press- stop your kidding: Princeton, Yale University, football
    State of the Union Sports Report to Congress
    Trick or Treat...shall we dance?: Dartmouth, Yale University, football
    Vote the Straight sports ticket: Boston Red Sox, boxing, golf, New York City
- Proofs and Tearsheet
  - 1970 (Oversize 1)
    [Yale University's Two Year Suspension by the NCAA] (2 copies)
    Sep 13: Sportslines...Love and Tears: demonstrations by football players in favor of a coaching change (photocopy of the original, note about Syracuse University written at top)
  - Undated (Oversize 1)
    Go Ahead. Read me the Funnies. I could use a laugh: college student demonstrations
    Oh! Somewhere in this favored land the sun is shining bright:...: college student demonstrations
    Where Have all the fans gone?: baseball, horse racing
    To Have and to Hold- for better and worse: National League baseball expansion